The blade pierces, the guts spill out,
利刃刺穿 内脏溢出
but they heal in a moment.
但在片刻之间愈合
The chief of Iwagakure was truly an immortal,
石隐村村长果然是永生的
thanks to a medicine he obtained long ago
多亏了他很久以前在大洋彼岸的
on a continent beyond the sea.
大陆上得到的一种药
Your face…
你的表情…
You didn't think it really existed, did you?
你没想到它确实存在吧？
Do you mean…?
你是说…
It does exist. The elixir of immortality,
是存在的 长生不老药
or the Tokijiku no Kagu no mi.
或是非时香果
I don't know if it's here, but…
我不知道是否在这里 但是…
This is…
这是…
Everything is so mystical.
一切都是那么神秘
I wouldn't be surprised
如果这里有长生不老药
if the elixir of immortality was here.
我一点也不会感到惊讶
You mean the scenery is eerie.
你是说这里的景色很怪异
All the plants here are different in species and habitat.
这里所有的植物在种类
It's just unnatural.
就是很不自然
Besides…
而且…
You never know what's out there.
你永远不知道外面有什么
We need to be on the lookout.
我们需要保持警惕
The hand ropes shall not be removed!
不要把绳子解开
Eh. How can I do anything if I'm tied up?
嗯？如果我被绑住了 还怎么做事？
Rules are rules.
规矩就是规矩
It's my job to watch over the criminals.
我的工作是看管犯人
If you break the rules, I can't overlook it.
如果你违反规则 我可不能忽视
Put your hand rope back on.
把你的绳子绑回去
Come on, give me a break.
拜托 让我休息一下吧
This isn't the only reckless thing either.
这也不是唯一粗心的事
We only have water and food for three days.
我们只有三天的食物和水
And only one clue.
并且只有一个线索
They have no intention of finding it, do they?
他们根本不想找到它吧？
Put your rope back on.
把你的绳子绑回去
Let me make it clear.
我再说清楚一些
I'm an executioner, not a collaborator.
我是刽子手 不是通敌者
If you fail to find the elixir and don't receive your full pardon,
如果你找不到灵药 没有得到你的完全赦免
it is none of my business.
这些都不关我的事
If you don't put the rope on, I'll cut off your head.
但如果你不系上绳子 我就砍下你的头
Fine then. Have it your way.
知道了 那就如你所愿吧
I just want to see my wife.
我只想见我的妻子
I'll accept your terms for that, but don't ask for too--
为了那个 我会接受你的条件
The first one is down.
第一个已经倒下了
You fool!
你这个笨蛋
To be careless in such a situation,
在这种情况下 这么不小心
you deserve to die.
是你自己该死
That surprised me.
你吓了我一跳
Are you okay?
你没事吧？
Yeah, I just dislocated my neck.
没事 只是脖子脱臼了
-Who is he anyway? -Um…
-话说 他是谁啊？ -呃…
He's a criminal on death row, the Warped Keiun.
他是死刑犯 扭曲庆云
During his training as a monk-soldier,
在他作为僧兵接受训练期间
he became fascinated by the armor itself.
他对武器本身着了迷
He's collected more than 100 pieces of armor from martial artists.
他收藏了100多件武术家的武器
No, what I want to know is…
不是 我想知道的是
Why is he not tied?
他为什么没有被绑起来？
No, that's not important now… No, what I mean is…
不是 那个现在不重要 不 我是说…
Sir, why is he not tied?
大人 为什么他没有被绑起来？
You're too serious about everything, Sagiri.
你对一切都太认真了 佐切
Just tie them up on the way back.
回去的时候把他们绑起来就行了
I can't be bothered by a bunch of idiots over something like that.
我可不想因为这样的事情 被一群白痴打扰
See, I told you so.
看吧 我说的吧
It's because of your foolish honesty that you're still below me.
你愚蠢的诚实让你仍然在我之下
We, the Asaemon are ranked. By the way, Sagiri is…
我们浅右卫门是有排名的 佐切依然是…
Now is not the time to talk about that…
现在不是说这些的时候
Are you ignoring me, Gabimaru the Hollow?
你是在无视我吗 空洞的画眉丸？
You are as bold and sturdy as you are rumored to be.
你跟传闻中一样勇敢和坚强
This is the perfect opportunity.
这是绝好的机会
I can now fully test my masterpiece!
现在我可以好好测试我的杰作了
Armor shines only when it sucks blood…
武器只有在吸血时才会发光
I will teach its beauty to you.
我会把它的美好教给你
Are you a pervert?
你是变态吗？
If we fight here now,
如果我们现在打架
the other guys will get ahead of us.
其他人会抢在我们前面
Let it be.
随他们去吧
We have no clues to begin with anyway.
反正我们也没什么线索
So, first, I'll kill all the criminals.
所以 首先 我要杀了所有罪犯
Then I'll slowly search for the elixir.
然后再慢慢地寻找灵药
-You are the first to die, Hollow. -Seriously?
-第一个死的会是你 空洞 -认真的吗？
We're just here to keep an eye on you.
我们只是在这里看着你
If you want to kill, be my guest.
如果你想杀人 就随便你吧
I agree.
同意
What a pain in the ass and a waste of time.
真是烦人 浪费时间
I don't want to do this because it would make my wife sad.
我不想这么做 因为这会让我妻子伤心
I have no choice, but to kill you.
没有选择了 只能杀了你
Show me what you got.
让我看看你的本事
-Your rope. -You're kidding, right?
-你的绳子 -你开玩笑的吧？
Alright, I got it tied.
好吧 系上了
This is my chance.
我的机会来了
Now, I can test all of my weapons on you!
现在我能在你身上测试我的武器了
I don't have the time for that.
我可没那个时间
He threw that huge body with just a single stick.
他用一根棍子 就把那个巨大的身体扔了出去
He threw him.
他把他扔了出去
This is hard to do, especially with hand ropes.
手被绑着还真是困难
He struck him with a blow?
一拳就击倒了？
The armor is directly sewn onto his skin.
盔甲直接缝在了他的皮肤上
He's out of the ordinary after all.
他果然不是平凡人
Come on, let the game begin.
来吧 游戏开始了
Gabimaru the…
画眉丸…
I wasted a lot of time.
我浪费了很多时间
Let's look for the elixir.
我们去找灵药吧
I've got my hand ropes on.
我的绳子已经系上了
Ah… yes.
好的
Well, I'll be leaving.
那么 我走了
You sure you don't want to fight?
你确定不想打架？
I told you, we are neither friend nor foe.
我说过 我们既不是朋友 也不是敌人
When the criminal we're in charge of dies,
当我们负责的罪犯死后
we bring back its head. That's all.
我们就把人头带回去 这样而已
I'm gonna go home and take a bath.
我要回家洗澡了
Sir,
大人
60 people are missing on this island.
有60人在这岛上失踪了
Please be careful on your way home.
回去的时候务必小心
You should be worrying about yourself.
你还是担心你自己吧
I'm lucky to get out of here so fast.
我很幸运 能这么快就离开这里
If you're relieved just because he's tied, you're too naive.
如果你认为他被绑着 你就能放心 那你就太天真了
You're standing next to a criminal.
你在一个罪犯身边
It's been a few hours since landing,
登岛才几个小时
but, I've already seen it.
但我都看到了
There are those who try to eliminate their opponent before landing.
有些人试图在登岛前 就消灭他们的对手
Those who plan to collude.
有些人计划勾结
And those who pretend to do so.
有些人假装勾结
Those who can't follow the rules of society in the first place.
有些人从一开始就不能遵守社会规则
Those who don't care about their roles or rules.
有些人不在乎规则或他们的角色
Each try to survive in their own way.
每个人都试图用自己的方式生存
They'll do whatever it takes.
他们会不惜一切代价
But, if they break the rules… isn't the letter of official release invalid?
但是 如果他们违反规则 赦免信不就无效了？
You're so serious about everything.
你对一切都太认真了
For a samurai, the lord's wishes are absolute,
对于武士来说 大人的意愿是毋庸置疑的
but what matters now is priority.
但现在重要的是优先级
Our priority now is the elixir. Everything else comes second.
我们现在的首要任务是找长生不老药 其他的都排在第二位
It's better to break the rules
打破规则
than to follow them and find nothing.
总好过一无所获
The Government would be more pleased.
那样幕府会更高兴
Rules are only valid
只有每个人都遵守
if everyone follows them.
规则才会有效
Some people don't follow the rules at all.
有些人根本不遵守规则
Just like that guy.
比如那个家伙
Maybe I'll… I'll slay you right now.
也许 我现在就该杀了你
Stop wasting your time. I don't have time for this.
别浪费你的时间了 我没有时间做这个
I just want to go home to my wife.
我只想回家见我的妻子
I don't care about anything else.
其他的我都不在乎
Let's get going.
我们开始吧
You're right, you better hurry.
说得没错 你最好快点
I'll tell you what's gonna happen.
我来告诉你会发生什么
In a few more hours, things are going to change.
再过几个小时 事情就会有变化
Hungry, Rokurota?
饿了吗 陆郎太？
In a few hours, the situation will be unpredictable.
几小时后
More than half will be dead,
半数以上的人会死
and in another few hours, the other half.
再过几小时 剩下的那一半也会死
In less than a day, you will be alone.
不到一天 你就会只身一人
You're all expendable after all.
毕竟你们都是消耗品
When we run out, we'll just add the next one.
当我们用完时 就添加下一个
The next one?
下一个？
I heard that Hattori's messenger flew to Ishu.
听说服部的使者已经飞往伊州
There's no mistake that the Government has made contact with the new Iwagakure.
去忍者村联系新人不是幕府的错
Asaemon is not a monolith, Sagiri.
浅右卫门不是单一群体 佐切
It is rumored
据传
that the next head of the Government will be decided by this role.
下一任幕府军首脑将由这个角色决定
I don't know if it's true or not, but…
我不知道这是不是真的 但是…
If so, you'll be against those with ambition.
如果是这样 那些有野心的人就会对付你
Not that I'm interested.
不过也不关我的事
See you later.
再见了
Don't let your guard down when dealing with sinners.
面对罪人时不要放松警惕
I've warned you.
我警告过你了
It's true…
是真的
Even after watching him for a few days,
即使看了他几天之后
I still can't grasp this man's true nature.
我还是看不清他的真面目
But…
但是…
So… where shall we go?
那么 我们该去哪里？
What are you doing?!
你在干什么呢？
I thought I'd kill you without causing you pain.
我想在不让你痛苦的情况下杀了你
As I thought…
和我想的一样
This man's true nature is…
这个男人的本性是…
As soon as he has a child, he wants to leave the village?
他一有孩子 就想离开村子？
It is shameful, even for a jonin.
真是可耻 即使是上忍也是
I will raise this child.
我会抚养这个孩子
Yes, sir.
是 大人
Take a good look, Gabimaru.
好好看看吧 画眉丸
This is weakness.
这就是弱点
If you have feelings for someone, even if it's a parent and child,
如果你对某人有感情 即使是父母和孩子
that in itself weakens you.
那本身就会让你变弱
If you are not strong, you cannot protect anything.
如果你不强大 你就无法保护任何东西
Anything that is important…
所有重要的东西
If you kill me, you will be breaking the rules.
如果你杀了我 你就会违反规则
Didn't your friend say that priority is key?
你朋友不是才说过优先级是关键吗？
If the Iwagakure land on the island,
如果石隐村忍者登陆到岛上
everything will come crashing down.
一切都会崩溃的
We must find the elixir before that happens.
我们必须在那之前找到灵药
I hold no grudge against you, but you're a nuisance.
我对你没有怨恨 但你是个讨厌鬼
So that's why… you're going to kill me?
所以你才要杀我？
When you have no choice, you have no choice.
别无选择就是别无选择
Sorry, but you're gonna die.
对不起 但你会死
This man is dangerous after all.
这个男人果然很危险
His thoughts and ethics are extreme and abnormal.
他的思想和伦理极端不正常
He should be executed immediately!
他应该立即被处决
And yet… I'm hesitant about it.
但我仍然犹豫不决
I can't… I just can't….
我…我做不到…
Again… She could have killed me now, but she didn't.
又是这样 她本可以现在就杀了我 但她没有
Why am I hesitating?
我为什么犹豫？
Why?
为什么？
Not wanting to kill is a natural thing, isn't it?
不想杀人 是很自然的事情 不是吗？
But I am Hollow.
但我是空洞的画眉丸
How can I have such feelings?
我怎么能有那种感觉呢？
What are you saying? You're a man who blushes after a mere kiss.
你在说什么呢？ 你可是连亲吻都会脸红的人
If you have feelings, follow them.
如果你有感觉 就跟随它们
You're no longer the same person you once were.
你已经不是以前的自己了
To be true to one's feelings is true courage.
忠于自己的感受才是真正的勇气
I will follow you.
我会追随你的
Even if I have to leave my village.
即使我不得不离开我的村庄
Meeting my wife, I learned to love.
遇见我的妻子 我学会了爱
But… I also learned to hate.
但是 我也学会了恨
That man is not our target.
那个人不是我们的目标
He said he would take revenge on me and my wife so…
他说他要报复我和我妻子 所以…
Please wait! I can't die!
请等一下 我不能死
I have a wife and child!
我有妻子和孩子
I learned weakness as well.
我也学会了弱点
Again… This is weakness.
又来了 这是弱点
If I don't do this, I won't be acquitted,
如果不这样做 我就不会被赦免
let alone survive here.
更不用说在这里生存
I'm dealing with a ferocious criminal.
我正在和一个凶残的罪犯打交道
On top of that, my life is in danger, yet….
更重要的是 我的生命处于危险之中 然而…
What a nuisance… the heart is.
我的心真是讨厌
If you're not strong, you can't protect anything.
如果你不强大 你就无法保护任何东西
Don't waste your time resisting.
别浪费时间抵抗了
You know what you're capable of.
你知道你的能力
You can't kill me with that.
你无法用那个杀了我
I wouldn't feel this way killing sinners,
我杀罪人不会有这种感觉
but it pains me to kill you.
但杀你让我痛苦
So please die peacefully.
所以请安详地死去吧
It pains you? You have such feelings in your heart?
让你痛苦？你心里有这样的感受？
I guess…
我想…
I have no heart.
我没有心
I am Gabimaru the Hollow.
我是空洞的画眉丸
I've killed more people than I can count.
我杀过的人数不胜数
Killing you won't make a difference.
多你一个也没有区别
I won't feel a thing.
我不会有任何感觉
That's how I was raised.
我就是这样长大的
If you're not strong, you can't protect anything.
如果你不强大 你就无法保护任何东西
This man is dangerous after all…
这个男人果然很危险
I don't want your mercy.
我不要你的怜悯
Please die.
请死去吧
And yet…
即使是这样…
Why…?
为什么…
Why do I hesitate?
我为什么犹豫？
Shouldn't I feel nothing?
我不是应该没有感觉吗？
I just realized…
我才意识到
That time… And that time too.
那次…那次也是
This man has always…
这个男人脸上
had that same look on his face.
总是有相同的表情
Those eyes, as if they are enduring something.
那双眼睛 好像在忍耐着什么
The environment in which he was born and raised in makes him do this.
他出生和成长的环境迫使他这样做
He is not a hollow man that doesn't feel anything.
他不是一个没有任何感觉的空心人
He's a man with feelings.
他是个有情感的人
I was also able to… face my true feelings
我也能够面对我的真实感受
because of him.
都是因为他
Have I…
我变得
become this weak?
这么弱了吗？
I can't survive like this…
这样我是无法生存下去的
I'll never see my wife, if I'm this weak.
如果我这么弱 我是无法再见到我妻子的
That is not weakness.
这不是弱点
It's a kind of strength.
这是一种力量
Believing you don't feel anything
相信自己什么都感觉不到
is the same as looking away.
就等同于视而不见
I believe that true strength is to
我相信真正的力量
not run away from your feelings.
是不去逃避你的感受
To be true to one's feelings is true courage.
忠于自己的感受才是真正的勇气
Let me just say this.
这么说吧
Because of you, I've been able to face my feelings.
因为你 我已经能够面对自己的感受了
How can you say that in this situation?
你怎么能在这种情况下说这种话？
You're the one who's holding back.
你才是那个退缩的人
I should give you the death penalty, but…
我应该判你死刑 但是
this time I'll overlook it.
这次我会视而不见
If you truly repent your sins, face your true self,
如果你真的忏悔你的罪行 面对真实的自己
and you're struggling to reclaim your life.
努力恢复你的生活
I want to see you do it.
我想看到你这么做
Please show me.
请让我看看
Whether a man like you can get his life back.
像你这样的人能否重获新生
I have to face myself too,
我也必须面对我自己
to become stronger.
这样才能变得更强
Our position won't change.
我们的立场不会改变
But you are…
但你…
You are no longer…
但你已经…
the same person you once were.
不是以前的自己了
What is this?
这是什么啊？
They look like… man-made objects.
它们看起来都像人造的
What the hell are you doing?
你在干什么？
-Why did you do that? -Look!
-你为什么这么做？ -看
It's a butterfly with a human face.
是长着人脸的蝴蝶
How can such things exist?
怎么会有这种东西存在？
-Amazing! -This is no time to be fascinated.
-好惊人 -现在不是看入迷的时候
What in the world is this island?
这个岛到底是什么？
Is this place really a paradise?
这个地方真的是天堂吗？
Biologically, it may be possible but…
从生物学上讲 是可能的 但是…
This is getting interesting.
事情变得有趣起来了
Interesting…
有意思
What is this… creature?
这是什么生物？
Stand back.
退后
Subtitle translation by: Mel Nishi
字幕翻译：朱未耒